<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<question id="2" level="2" subject="Graphs">

	<text>
       <p>Perform Depth-first search on the following graph. Whenever there is a choice of vertices, pick one that is alphabetically first. Classify each edge as: TREE edge, FORWARD edge, BACK edge or CROSS edge and the respective PRE and POST number of each vertex, in order to answer the correct question. </p>
       <img src="images/graph01.png"/>
  </text>

    <explanation>
        <i>>The correct classification of edges and the correct PRE/POST ordering for vertex of the graph are:
<p>BACK edges: (g,b), (i,c), (d,a) - Back edges lead to an ancestor in the DFS tree.</p>
<p>CROSS edges: (c,b), (d,h) - Cross edges lead to neither descendant nor ancestor; they therefore lead to a node that has already been completely explored (that is, already postvisited).</p>
FORWARD edges: none - Forward edges lead from a node to a nonchild descendant in the DFS tree.
<p>PRE/POST of each vertex: A:1/18, B:2/11, C:12/17, D:13/16, E:3/10, F:4/9, G:5/8, H:6/7, I:14/15</p></i>
    </explanation>

	<choice type="correct">
		<text>There are exactly: 3 BACK edges and 2 CROSS edges</text>
		<explanation>
			
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="correct">
		<text>The following PRE/POST are correct: A is: 1/18, C is 12/17, I is 14/15. Additionally, we can conclude by those PRE/POST that the edge (i,c) is a BACK edge</text>
		<explanation>
			
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="correct">
		<text>The following PRE/POST are correct: A is: 1/18, B is 2/11, G is 5/8. Additionally, we can conclude by those PRE/POST that the edge (g,b) is a BACK edge</text>
		<explanation>
			
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="false">
		<text>There are exactly: 3 BACK edges, 1 FORWARD edges and and 1 CROSS edge</text>
		<explanation>
			There is no FORWARD edge in the graph. There are only TREE, BACK and CROSS edges.
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="false">
		<text>There are exactly: 3 BACK edges and 0 CROSS edges</text>
		<explanation>Note that there are CROSS edges in the graph. For example, the edge (c,b) is a CROSS edge since this specific edge lead to neither descendant nor ancestor. Therefore this edge lead to a node that has already been completely explored.
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="false">
		<text>There are exactly: 2 BACK edges and 2 CROSS edges</text>
		<explanation>There are 3 BACK edges in total. The following are BACK edges: (g,b), (d,a), (i,c)
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="false">
		<text>There are exactly: 2 BACK edges, 8 FORWARD edges and 3 CROSS edge</text>
		<explanation>
			Note that edges that are actually part of the DFS forest are called TREE edges instead of FORWARD edges.
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="false">
		<text>There are exactly: 2 BACK edges and 3 CROSS edge</text>
		<explanation>
			There are 3 BACK edges in total. The following are BACK edges: (g,b), (d,a), (i,c). Also check the number of CROSS edges again.
		</explanation>
	</choice>
	<choice type="false">
    		<text>The following PRE/POST are correct: A is: 1/18, B is 3/12, G is 6/9. Additionally, we can conclude by those PRE/POST that the edge (g,b) is a BACK edge</text>
    		<explanation>Check the PRE/POST ordering for nodes B and G. Remember that whenever there is a choice of vertices, you must pick one that is alphabetically first.
		</explanation>
  	</choice>
  	<choice type="false">
    		<text>The following PRE/POST are correct: E is: 3/10, F is 5/8, G is 5/8. Additionally, we can conclude by those PRE/POST that the edge (i,c) is a BACK edge </text>
    		<explanation>
		This is not correct, since the vertex I and vertex C PRE/POST were not mentioned. Also the PRE/POST of vertex F is not correct.
		</explanation>
  	</choice>
  	<choice type="false">
    		<text>BACK edges lead to an ancestor in the DFS tree and CROSS edges lead to a node that has not been completely discovered. Using this definitions, we can point out that (g,b) is a BACK edge and (c,b) is a CROSS edge </text>
    	<explanation>
	The definiton of CROSS edge is not correct. Note that by the time we examine (c,b), vertex B has been completely discovered.
	</explanation>
  	</choice>
  	<choice type="false">
    		<text>The following PRE/POST are correct: A is: 1/19, B is 2/11, I is 14/15, D is 13/16. </text>
    		<explanation>the PRE/POST of vertex A is not correct. The correct PRE/POST for vertex A is: 1/18
		 </explanation>
	</choice>


</question>
